A Guide to the Duncan A. MacInnes papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA178
Rockefeller Archive Center
Duncan A. MacInnes papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1926-1965
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
MacInnes, Duncan A. (Duncan Arthur)
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA178
9.24 Cubic Feet
20 boxes; 2 volumes and envelope
Biographical/Historical note
Duncan-Arthur MacInness, 1885-1965, scientist in physical chemistry worked at The Rockefeller University (earlier RIMR) from 1926 until his death in 1965.
He was the author of The Principles of Electrochemistry and numerous contributions to scientific publications and mountaineering magazines.
Biographical note
1885 Born March 31, Salt Lake City, Utah
1907 B.S. University of Utah
1909 M.S. University of Illinois, Urbana
1911 Ph. D. University of Illinois, Urbana
1911-1914 Instructor in physical chemistry, University of Illinois, Urbana
1914-1917 Associate in physical chemistry, University of Illinois, Urbana
1917-1921 Assistant professor, physical chemistry, MIT, Cambridge, Mass.
1921-1926 Associate professor in physical chemistry, MIT, Cambridge, Mass.
1926-1940 Associate Member, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, New York
1940 Sigma Xi lecturer
1940-1950 Member, RIMR
1942 William H. Nichols Medal, American Chemical Society
1943 Priestley lecturer, Pennsylvania State College
1948 President's Certificate of Merit for War Researches
1948 Edward Goodrich Acheson Medal of Electrochemical Society
1950 Member Emeritus, RIMR
1965 Died September 23, Hanover, New Hampshire
Member of: American Physical Society, Fellow, National Academy of Sciences, American Chemical Society, American Electrochemical Society (President 1935-1937), American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Harvey Society, American Philosophical Society
Scope and Contents note
Includes photographs, mss., reprints, journals; war contract Duncan, material.
Arrangement note
Arranged in chronological order within subject.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
MacInnes papers, along with the residue and remainder of his property both real and personal were bequeathed by will, unrestricted to The Rockefeller University.
Received or inventoried: April/May 1974.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 M189
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
World War II; Chemical warfare; Chemical warfare -- Research -- United States; Chemistry; Biochemistry; Electrochemistry; Rockefeller University; MacInnes, Duncan A. (Duncan Arthur); Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Biographical materials, 1
  Scope and Contents
  Includes bibliography, personal correspondence, financial records, personal and family photographs, and will.
  - Biographical materials, 1926-1948 1974 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Autobiographical sketch including two additional holograph pages; account of laboratory researches 1926-1948; bibliography; Public Relations obituary; 2 page summary of biography written by Lewis G. Longsworth (written for RU exhibit, summer 1974 Burial certificate and note of interment).
  - Personal correspondence, 1907-1960 1961-1965 (Box 1)
    Arrangement note
    Arranged in chronological order and personal.
    - Letters written to mother, 1907; 2 items, holograph
    - correspondence dealing with criticism of guides on Mt. Rainier and related to article appearing in Appalachia, 1936-1940
    - correspondence with Macy's Department Store to protest handling of Blanchards "American Freedom and Catholic Power", 1949
    - correspondence on 65th birthday, 1950
      Arranged in alphabetical order.
      - Acree, S.F., holograph
      - Aunt Fanny
      - Beattie, James A.
      - Belcher, Donald, holograph
      - Berdick, J. & M., drawing
      - Blum, W.
      - Brown, Alfred, holograph
      - Cowperthwaite, I., holograph
      - Dole, Malcolm, holograph
      - Ecker, Paul G., holograph
      - Harris, Louis, telegram
      - Kobelt, Nina, holograph
      - Miller, Mary L., holograph
      - Perlmann, G.E., holograph
      - Ray, Roger & D., telegram
      - Risk, Louise, telegram
      - Scotchald (sp.?) G., holograph
      - Smith, Edgar Reynolds
      - Uhlig, Herbert
    - Some letters of complaint to NY Central; A&P; Macy's
    - Stuart Jeffery Bates, 1955
    - Financial matters: investments, sale of apartment, social Security, TIAA, complaints of noise in apartment, 1959
    - letters from sister Jean traveling abroad, 1960
    - Guggenheim Fellowship recommendation for Reginald Laubin, 1961
    - report from physician, 1961
    - holograph letter from Harlow [Shapley], 1961
    - correspondence with Museum of Fine Arts, Boston and Massachusetts College of Art regarding statuette of D. MacInnes done by Cyrus Dallin, 1962-1963
    - correspondence with Samuel M. Goudsmit about a working space at Brookhaven National Lab, 1964
    - Letter to D.W. Bronk discontinuing work at Institute laboratory, 1965 March 18; copy
    - Correspondence with E.R. Smith and Charles A. Kraus regarding membership in the Cosmos Club, 1965
  - Cottage in Ft. Montgomery, NY including deed of purchase, correspondence and repairs (Box 1)
  - Financial records from 1956, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Income tax returns and correspondence, 1942-1951 (Box 1)
  - Biographical memoir, National Acad. of Sciences 41, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Passports and affidavit of birth date (Box 1)
  - Photographs of Dr. MacInnes, family and laboratory associates (Box 1)
  - Outdoors, 1941 (Box 1)
    Includes incomplete essay "Enjoying the Outdoors" (typed and holograph) correspondence from companions; American Alpine Club; Appalachian Mountain Club (including Conservation Committee); Representatives and Senators and Gov. Nelson Rockefeller.
    Includes copy of Appalachia, June 1941.
  - Rockefeller Institute memos (very scattered) (Box 1)
  - Will (Box 1)
- Journals, 1933-1959 (lack 1953-1957) 1910-1914 1925-1958; 2
  - Diaries, Primarily typewritten accounts. (Box 2)
    - 1933 July 8-1934 July, 44 pp.
    - 1944 October 18-1945 December 21, 143 pp.
    - 1946 January 2-1947 December 30, 169 pp.
    - 1948 January 4-1948 December 31, 105 pp.
    - 1949 January 3-1949 December 31, 114 pp
    - 1950 January 6-1950 December 20, 105 pp.
    - 1951 January 4-1951 December 20, 74 pp
    - 1952 January 4-1952 August 31, 69 pp.
    - 1958 March 3-1959 April 7, 11 pp.
  - Mimeographed copy A.L. Nadai "Trip to Moscow", 1945 (Box 2)
  - Diaries, 13 handwritten bound notebooks. (Box 3)
    Accounts of trips.
    - 1910-1914
    - England, 1925
    - 1930
      - A.M.C. trip New Hampshire (Box 3)
      - August Glacier Park, Montana, 1934-1935 (Box 3)
    - 1934-1935
      - Mt. Rainier National Park, July 25-September 10 (Box 3)
      - Banff-Crater Lake, July 13-August 11 (Box 3)
    - 1936
      - New York; Swarthmore, 1936 July 1-8 (Box 3)
      - Glacier Park, 1936 July 15-18 (Box 3)
    - Yellowstone National Park, 1936 August 10-September 13 (Box 3)
    - European trip, 1939 July 12-September 18 (Box 3)
    - Moscow trip, 1945 June-July (Box 3)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 3)
      - Wind River Range, July 5-August 31
      - Grand Teton, July 17-September 2
    - White Mountains, 1948 July 12-August 28
    - Italy, Sweden, Denmark, 1956 September 4-October 3
    - Iceland, Norway, 1958 July 31-September 10
    - Cash accounts and appointment book, 1959
  - Folder of mementos, photographs, photocopy of newspaper items on Moscow trip (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1941-1963; 3 (Box 4)
  Arranged in alphabetical order by correspondent including incoming and outgoing letters. Number in parenthesis indicates number of items. If only one item present name not listed unless of special interest.
  - A (Box 4)
    - Acree, S.F., 9 items
    - Adam, N.V. University College, Southampton, 4 items
    - Adams, Roger University of Illinois, Urbana, 1 item
    - Addicks, Lawrence (Low-melting alloys), 6 items
    - Albert, A. Adrian (Mathematics conference), 4 items
    - American Russian Institute
    - Amis, Edward S. University of Arkansas, 3 items
    - Anderson, Leroy (Standard cell comparator), 4 items
    - Apt, Charles M., 4 items
    - Armstrong, H. Howard (Radio wave theory), 6 items
    - Audubert, Rene (visit to RIMR), 11 items
  - B (Box 4)
    - Baker, Philip S. (Calomel-mercury electrode), 4 items
    - Bates, Stuart California Institute of Technology, 4 items
    - Beams, J.W. Rouss Physical Laboratory, 21 items
    - Beattie, James A.M.I.T., 7 items
    - Birge, R.T. (value of the Faraday), 3 items
    - Bjerrum, Jannik, 3 items
    - Bjerrum, Niels, 3 items
    - Blinks, Lawrence, 16 items
    - Blum, W. National Bureau of Standards, 10 items
    - Bockris, J. O'M, 3 items
    - Bronk, Detlev National Academy of Sciences, 42 items
    - Brown, Alfred Seely, 11 items
    - Brown, Weldon G., 2 items
    - Burdick, C. Lalor, 3 items
    - Burgess, Laurie L., 3 items
    - Burns, R.M., 15 items
    - Butcher, Devereux. National Parks Assoc, 8 items
    - Butler, J.A.V., 7 items
  - C (Box 4)
    - Campbell, Edwin S., 2 items
    - Cann, John R., 4 items
    - Carmichael, E.S. (Nichol's Award Dinner), 4 items
    - Cazier, Mont. A. (includes some APS items), 20 items
    - Charlwood, P.A. National Research Council, Canada, 6 items
    - Chemical and Engineering News, 4 items
    - Chu, Ting Li, 4 items
    - Chu, V.G., 5 items
    - Cirker, Hayward (Dover Publications - includes several correspondents), 28 items
    - Clark, W. Mansfield, 12 items
    - Clarke, Hans T., 4 items
    - Clarkson, James A., 6 items
    - Coggeshall, L.T., 3 items
    - Cohn, Edwin J., 4 items
    - Cole, Kenneth S., 4 items
    - Cole, Robert H., 4 items
    - Condon, E.U. National Bureau of Standards, 7 items
    - Corner, George W., 4 items
    - Cottrell, E.G. holograph, 2 items
    - Cox, Edward II, 5 items
  - D (Box 4)
    - Darrow, Karl K., 6 items
    - Davies, R.H., 4 items
    - Dayhoff, Margaret, 18 items
    - Dodson, R.W., 11 items
    - Doerr, John E. National Park Service, 7 items
    - Dole, Malcolm, 4 items
    - Dryden, Hugh L, 10 items
    - Dubisson, M., 10 items
    - DuMond, Jesse W.M., 28 items
    - Dunn, Leslie C. (Concerning Am. Soviet Science Society), 4 items
  - E (Box 4)
    - Ecker, Paul G., 23 items
    - Edsall, John T., 4 items
    - Einstein, A. (form letter Emergency Committee Atomic Scientists)
    - Eisenhart, L.P. American Philosophical Society, 17 items
    - Ellis, Ridsdale, 4 items
    - Emery, Alden H., 4 items
    - Encyclopedia of Science and Technology, 4 items
    - Engel, Leonard, 4 items
    - Eppley, Marion, 10 items
  - F (Box 5)
    - Farrer, H.E., 3 items
    - Fine, M.S., 6 items
    - Fite, W. Benjamin, 5 items
    - Flexner, Simon, 6 items
    - Flinn, Waldo, 17 items
    - Forrester, Jay (Am. Soviet Science Society), 2 items
    - Fosbroke, Gerald E. (Appalachian Mountain Club), 3 items
    - Frazier, John Franklin Institute Medal to Arne Tislius, 13 items
    - Frumkin, A.N. (Colloido-Electrochemical Inst., Moscow), 2 items
    - Fruton, Joseph S., 3 items
      Includes holograph note.
    - Fuoss, Raymond M., 18 items
  - G (Box 5)
    - Galtsoff, Paul S., 3 items
    - Gauss, E.J. (Kelvin water dropper), 3 items
    - Gertsch, Willis. American Philosophical Society, 4 items
    - Gilman, Bradley B. American Alpine Club, 3 items
    - Glocker, George, 4 items
    - Goddard, David R., 4 items
    - Gordon, A.R., 9 items
    - Goudsmit, Samuel A., 6 items
    - Gowen, John W., 3 items
    - Graff, Henry F., 2 items
    - Grahame, David C., 2 items
    - Greenspan, J., 3 items
    - Greenwood, Norman N., 3 items
    - Gregor, H.P., 2 items
    - Grundfest, Harry, 7 items
    - Guggenheim, E.A., 6 items
    - Gurney, Ronald W., 3 items
    - Gustafson, Carl O. Council of Conservation, 3 items
  - H (Box 5)
    - Hamer, Walter J. National Bureau of Standards, 1947-1963; 59 items
    - Hab-Het
    - Haber & Fink, 5 items
    - Hall, Norris F., 2 items
    - Ham, Rosewell G., 2 items
    - Hamilton, E.P., 2 items
    - Hammett, Louis P., 2 items
    - Harned, Herbert S., 1948-1962; 48 items, many holograph letters
    - Harnwell, Gaylord P., 11 items
    - Harris, Helen M. Am. Soviet Science Society, 3 items
    - Harrison, George P., 5 items
    - Hart, R.A., 2 items
    - Hartley, Harold, 6 items
    - Hartline, H.K. APS grant application, 1 item
    - Hattery, Lowell H., 2 items
    - Hawley, G.G. Reinhold Pub, 4 items
    - Heidelberger, Michael Conference on Immunochemistry, 16 items
    - Heiman, Jacob. Am. Soviet Science Society, 7 items
    - Herriott, Roger M., 4 items
    - Hetland, Enok, 26 items
  - Hew-Huy (Box 5)
    - Hewitt, William F. Am. Soviet Science Society, 2 items
    - Hiatt, C.W., 1947-1960; 43 items
      Includes college record, application.
    - Hildebrand, Joel H., 4 items
    - Hill, Arthur, 11 items
    - Hodgman, Charles D. Handbook of Chemistry and Physics, 3 items
    - Hollaender, Alexander, 14 items
    - Hood, Harrison P., 4 items
    - Hoyman, Scott M., 5 items
    - Humphreys, Harrie M., 4 items
    - Hunt, Everett Lee, 3 items
    - Huntoon, R.D. National Bureau of Standards, 4 items
    - Hurd, Marjorie. Appalachian Mt. Club, 3 items
  - I (Box 5)
    - Iliff, J.W. John Scott Award for J.W. Beams, 2 items
    - International Congress on Fundamental Physical Constants, 1956; 10 items
  - J (Box 5)
    - Jacobs, Thomas L., 2 items
    - Jacobson, C.F., 2 items
    - Jacoby, Kurt, 2 items
    - Janz, George J., 5 items
    - Jenkins, D.J. with enclosure, 3 items
    - Jewett, Frank B. 1945-47 National Academy of Science Conference, 1945-1947; 31 items
    - Johnson, Frank H., 6 items
    - Johnson, James S., 2 items
    - Jones, Grinnell. Re: Benj. C. Bradshaw, 1 item
    - Journal of Physical Chemistry, 6 items
  - K (Box 5)
    - Kay, Robert L., 1952-1959; 38 items
    - Kat, 11 items
    - Katavalos, Peter Conference arrangements at Ram's Head Inn
    - Katchalsky, A., 2 items
    - Kauzman, Walter, 2 items
    - Kelly, Harry C., 2 items
    - Keyes, F.G. Am. Soviet Science Society, 4 items
    - Kilpatrick, M., 6 items
    - King, William H., 3 items
    - Kirk, Raymond E., 5 items
    - Kirkwood, John G. Also Conference on Statistical Mechanics, 1945-1956; 28 items
    - Kirner, Walter R. National Science Foundation grants (Kovach, Jonich), 27 items
    - Kistiakowsky, G.B. Charles B. Smyth nomination Nat'l Acad Sci, 6 items
    - Kittelberger, W.W., 5 items
    - Klinefelter, Earl. ACS Committee on Awards, 7 items
    - Koenig, Frederick O., 9 items
    - Kolthoff, I.M., 7 items
    - Kratz, Paul H., 2 items
    - Kraus, K.A., 8 items
    - Kuemmerle, K., 2 items
  - L (Box 6)
    - Lalor Foundation, 5 items
    - Lamb, Arthur B., 10 items
    - LeMer, Victor K., 28 items
    - Lancefield, Rebecca [Electrophoretic analysis), 2 items
    - Latimer, W.M., 4 items
    - Laubin, R. & G. Indian dances, 6 items
    - Lauffer, Max (Chemical kinetics), 2 items
    - Lee, James A. Chemical Engineering, 4 items
    - LeRoy, D.J. On membership in NY Acad of Sci, 2 items
    - Lilienthal, David. In support of, 3 items
    - Linderstrøm-Lang, K., 5 items
    - Linford, Henry B. Electrochemical Society, 7 items
    - Livingston, Robert B. Nat'l Acad, of Sci, 2 items
    - Longsworth, Lewis. holograph re Harry Svensson, 1 item
  - M (Box 6)
    - MacDougall, F.H. Recommendation of B. Roger Ray, 3 items
    - Macurdy, L.B. Nat'l Bureau of Standards, 6 items
    - Malcove, Lillian. Recommendation of Paul G. Ecker, 2 items
    - Marlett, Russell, 4 items
    - Marvel, C.S. Nat'l Acad. Sci. nominations, 8 items
    - Mathews, J.H. Recommendation B. Roger Ray, 3 items
    - Maxwell, I.R. Pergamon Press - Langmuir Memorial Edition, 3 items
    - Mayer, Joseph E. Journal of Chemical Physics, 11 items
    - McMeekin, T.L., 4 items
    - Medal of Merit correspondence
    - Mendenhall, E.E., 4 items
    - Merriman, Daniel, Sigma Xi lecture, 7 items
    - Miller, Donald, 7 items
    - Miller, Mary L., Nomination Garvan Medal Award, 6 items
    - Mirsky, Alfred E., 5 items
    - Mohler, Fred Nat'l Bureau of Standards, 3 items
    - Muller, H.J. Security clearance re. Dr. Stadler, 6 items
  - N (Box 6)
    - Nachmansohn, David, 4 items
    - Nadai, A. on Moscow trip, 2 items
    - National Bureau of Standards Varied correspondents; enclosures, 25 items
    - Naval Research Office of, 4 items
    - Neurath, Hans, 7 items
    - Nichols, Roy F. Am. Philosophical Society, 2 items
    - Nier, Alfred O.C., 4 items
    - Nobel Committee for Chemistry, 5 items
    - Noonan, J.A. Am. Philosophical Society, 8 items
    - Norris, Earl R., 6 items
    - Northrop, John H., 7 items
    - Noyes, W. Albert Journal of the American Chemical Society, 30 items
    - Nuovo Cimento, 3 items
  - O (Box 6)
    - Odishaw, Hugh Loyalty question, 2 items
    - Onsager, Lars, 10 items
    - Oster, Gerald, 7 items
    - Osterhout, W.J.V. 2 holograph letters, 10 items
    - Overbeek, J. Th. G., 3 items
    - Oviatt, Charles McGraw Hill, 7 items
    - Owen, Benton B., 9 items
  - P (Box 6)
    - Packard, Fred M. National Parks Assoc, 9 items
    - Pauling, Linus, 13 items
    - Pearson, Frank, 2 items
    - Pecsok, Robert L., 4 items
    - Pederson, K.O., 3 items
    - Pegram, George B., 4 items
    - Perley, George B. Leeds and Northrop Co., 4 items
    - Perlmann, Gertrude many handwritten, 11 items
    - Pillemer, Louis, 4 items
    - Plyler, Earl K. Nat'l Bureau of Standards, 3 items
    - Pope, Arthur Upham Iranian Institute; Vosmay Club, 5 items
    - Prentice, Donald B. Society of Sigma Xi, 4 items
    - Pray, Alfred R. Many holograph letters; includes photo, 45 items
  - R (Box 6)
    - Ray, B. Roger, 1944-1955; 97 items
  - R-Ry (Box 6)
    - Rabinowitch, Eugene Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 2 items
    - Raffel, B.D., 2 items
    - Ramsey, J.B., 2 items
    - Randolph, Malcolm, 3 items
    - Reinhold Publishing Corp., 4 items
    - Reyerson, L.H. University of Minnesota, 4 items
    - Rhoads, CP, 4 items
    - Rivers, Thomas M. Vice-Pres. RIMR, 12 items
    - Robbins, William J. American Philosophical Society, 10 items
    - Ross, Arthur M. Dinner honoring Prof. Harned, 2 items
    - Ross, Sydney, 2 items
    - Rous, Peyton, 2 items
    - Rousselot, Albert, 4 items
    - Rubens, S.M., 3 items
    - Rubicon Company, 4 items
    - Rukeyser, Muriel telegram re. petition behalf Hollywood Ten
    - Russian Relief Inc., 3 items
  - Ri (Box 6)
    - Richards, A. Nat'l Acad. Sci. - Shelter Island Conferences, 37 items
  - S-Sha (Box 7)
    - Sabin, Florence, 4 items
    - Sadek, Hussein, 3 items
    - Sadler, Monroe S., 8 items
    - Salzberg, Hugh W., 2 items
    - Sanford, Raymond L. Nat'l Bureau Standards, 7 items
    - Sanigar, Edward B. Electrochemical Society, 5 items
    - Scratchard, George, 9 items
    - Scheludko, A., 5 items
      Includes reprint.
    - Schneirla, T.C. Am. Philosophical Soc. grants, 3 items
    - Schrage, S., 2 items
    - Schumann, K., 5 items
    - Science, 2 items
    - Scientific American, 9 items
    - Scott, Arthur F., 4 items
    - Sears, Paul B. Mountain climbing, 4 items
    - Seifriz, William, 12 items
    - Sendroy, Julius, Jr., 4 items
    - Shapley, Harlow, 32 items
  - She-Smith (Box 7)
    - Sigurdsson, Bjorn, 3 items
    - Slater, John C., 8 items
    - Smillie, Wilson G., 2 items
    - Smith, Edgar Reynolds. Nat'l Bureau Standards, 22 items
    - Smith, Edric B., 14 items
    - Smith, Jessica. Soviet Russia Today, 4 items
    - Smith, Paul A. Nat'l Academy Sci, 18 items
  - Smy (Box 7)
    - Smyth, Charles P., 1954; 25 items
      Includes addresses 1954 Nichols Award.
  - Sn-Sz (Box 7)
    - Sollner, Karl, 6 items
    - Spedding, F.H., 4 items
    - Sporck, Christian R., 4 items
    - Stadler, L.J. Loyalty Board, 6 items
    - Stanley, Wendell M., 3 items
    - Stern, Kurt G., 4 items
    - Steuer, Rosemary. Camping, 3 items
    - Stewart, Florence M. Studies of RIMR, 34 items
    - Stewart, John Q., 4 items
    - Stillman, Calvin W. Conservation, 3 items
    - Stockmayer, Walter H., 3 items
    - Stoenner, R.W., 2 items
    - Stokes, R.H., 2 items
    - Straumanis, Martin E., 3 items
    - Sundaram, S.P., 3 items
    - Svedberg, The, 6 items
    - Svensson, Harry, 4 items
    - Swartout, J.A., 4 items
    - Szent-Gyorgyi, A., 4 items
  - T (Box 7)
    - Tait, Andrew. Recommendation, 8 items
    - Tarter, H.V., 6 items
    - Taub, David. Recommendation, 3 items
    - Taube, Henry A.C.S. lecture at Cornell, 12 items
    - Thomas, Elbert. Loyalty investigations, 4 items
    - Thomas, Henry, 4 items
    - Thompson, James S., 4 items
    - Thomsen, John S., 4 items
    - Tiselius, Arne, 9 items
    - Tobias, Charles W., 2 items
    - Tolman, Richard C., 3 items
    - Topp, N.E., 5 items
    - Trambarulo, Ralph, 3 items
    - Treadwell, W.D., 4 items
    - Trytlen, M.H., 4 items
    - Turner, Francis M. Reinhold Publishing, 6 items
  - U-V (Box 7)
    - Uhlig, H.H., 24 items
    - Urey, Harold C. Signed typescript, 2 items
    - Van Slyke, Donald, 18 items
    - Vinal, George W. Nat'l Bureau Standards, 20 items
    - Vincent, George D., 4 items
  - W (Box 7)
    - Way, Harold E., 3 items
    - Weaver, Warren, 6 items
    - Weigl, John W., 5 items
    - Whitaker, Douglas, 14 items
    - Whitney, Willis R., 4 items
    - Wilks, S.S. Nat'l Acad. Sci. Conferences, 5 items
      - Williams, John V. Conference on Ultra centrifuge, 7 items
      - Wilshusen, Herbert F., 6 items
      - Wilson, E.B. Nat'l Academy of Science, 21 items
      - Wilson, Perry W., 3 items
      - Wright, Donald D., 3 items
      - Whe
      - Wheeler, John A. 1946-48 Conference on Quantum Mechanics, 1946-1948; 25 items
    - X-Y-Z
      - Yoshimura, Hisato, 4 items
      - Young, Donald, 2 items
      - Young, Duane E., 4 items
      - Young, T.F., 6 items
      - Zuot, M., 2 items
      - Zweifel, R.G., 3 items
      - Zworykin, V.K., 3 items
- Subject files, 4 (Box 8)
  Subject files as maintained by Duncan A. MacInnes.
  - Correspondence (Box 8)
    Correspondence primarily between 1952-1964.
    Arranged in alphabetical order by subject.
    - American Chemical Society. Committee on Awards, 1959-1964
      - Nominations of Lyman Craig, Lewis G. Longsworth, Herbert S. Harned
    - American Philosophical Society, 1954-1963
      - Correspondence as member of committee on research grants and election to membership of Herbert S. Harned, and as member of Lewis Prize Committee
    - Bibliographies and biographical sketches used in various nominations: Herbert S. Harned; Lewis G. Longsworth; Theodore Shedlovsky; Victor K. LaMer
    - Budgets and statements at Rockefeller University, 1959 1965-1966
    - Calibration certificates from National Bureau of Standards: Mueller Bridge; Resistances; Standard Cells; Weights
    - Criticism: (comments and correspondence as referee for Journal of American Chemical Society; Journal of Physical Chemistry.) Arranged alphabetically by first author
    - Electrochemical Society
      Includes abstract of "A redetermination of the Value of the Faraday with the Iodine Coulometer" and carbon copy of "Josiah Willard Gibbs and the Hall of Fame".
    - National Academy of Sciences. Primarily material on ballots
    - National Academy of Sciences. Committee on Battery Additives. Primarily duplicated material
    - National Research Council. Conference on Number Theory and Class Field Theory
    - National Science Foundation, 1952-1955 1957-1963